Diner's Menu Offer Sparks Debate: Is it Really Sexist?
A restaurant's special ‘girlfriend’ offer is lighting up the internet and sparking debate about possible sexism.
It all began in June when Nick Chisler posted a photo on his Facebook page of a menu option titled "My Girlfriend Is Not Hungry."
He took the photo at an Arkansas diner he was eating at, and it gave him a chuckle.
The cheeky menu option at Mama D's Diner charges $4.25 for adding extra french fries to your order, and a choice of two fried chicken wings or three fried cheese sticks.
Chisler's post quickly became a hot topic on social and mainstream media, getting some 22,000 likes and receiving roughly 5,700 comments.
The online comments ran the gamut from a Facebook user who called it "an option you should always order because, you know, girlfriends always get snacky,"
to a Twitter user who said the menu option was a "marriage-saving" kind of idea.
But others were not amused. One person posted, "It is usually my boyfriend who isn't hungry," and another said, "It works both ways."
On Eater, a food-review website, Jaya Saxena blasted the offer for fueling the notion that women are "always being coy" and, in a worst-case scenario, are "always secretly looking for attention." The story circulated all the way to the Middle East, where women in Egypt and Jordan gave it a pass. "I'm not offended by it, but since we live in a world where everything and everyone is overly sensitive about the silliest things—I think it should be called the ‘partner option’ rather than the ‘girlfriend option.’ It can work both ways after all," said a 23-year-old Jordanian national.